<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Raymond Huang</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000" />
<updated>2016-02-05T00:59:30-08:00</updated>
<id>http://localhost:4000/</id>
<author>
  <name>Raymond Huang</name>
  <uri>http://localhost:4000/</uri>
  <email>huangrayr@gmail.com</email>
</author>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Sam Harris And Ethical Bedrock]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/sam-harris-and-ethical-bedrock/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/sam-harris-and-ethical-bedrock</id>
  <published>2015-01-15T18:09:50-08:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-15T18:09:50-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Raymond Huang</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@raymondhuang.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;This video is a conversation between Cenk Uygur and Sam Harris where they hash out their similarities and differences. More importantly, Harris is allowed to fully explain his view points. In other popular YouTube videos involving Sam Harris, such as the famous &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vln9D81eO60&quot; title=&quot;Bill Maher, Ben Afflect and Sam Harris debate&quot;&gt;Bill Maher, Ben Afflect and Sam Harris debate&lt;/a&gt;, his arguments tend to be interrupted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/WVl3BJoEoAU&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last 10 minutes of the conversation where Harris delivers his closing statements is particularly interesting. Harris portrays himself as a philosopher and states that much of his discussions have nothing to do with public policies but have been “an effort to get at ethical bedrock”. He explains that “in the context of having a philosophical discussion about [the] ethics and right and wrong”, seemingly crazy but legitimate arguments can surface. As an example, Harris poses a question: “What’s wrong with eating babies if there are extra babies?”. When quoted out of context, the question and the discussion surrounding the question is absurd. However, when trying to get to the bedrock about the ethics of good and evil, forming an ethical argument about why eating babies is wrong and why “intuitions of its wrongness can be conserved” is a legitimate conversation for philosophers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever Harris is interviewed, his arguments regarding inflammatory issues such as nuclear deterrence, torture, and the link between belief and action, are made “in the context of a very extensive conversation in philosophical terms” about how to get to ethical bedrock.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the end of the interview, Harris uses Osama bin Laden to demonstrate an ethical argument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“What makes it right to kill Osama bin Laden?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Is it right by virtue of all the people bin Laden has killed?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;No. We’re not certain Osama bin Laden personally killed anyone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Is it right by virtue of all the people that Al-Qaeda killed already?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;No. Killing Osama bin Laden does not bring anyone back to life, nor does it help anybody that is already killed, nor does it help the victims’ families.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Killing Osama bin Laden is the appropriate course of action if he could not be captured. The argument for killing him is not retribution, but is based on what bin Laden is aspiring to do in the future - all the people that are going to be saved if he is dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a world of memes, sound bites and GIFs, not many people have been to a philosophical seminar. As a consequence, Harris pays a massive penalty for trying to have a fine-grained academic discussion because his words are being exported onto Twitter by public individuals like “Glenn Greenwald and Reza Aslan who do not [engage] with [his] arguments closely enough” and choose to “cynically mislead people” regarding Harris’ point of view. In closing, Harris admits that when arguing about the ethics of torture, the conversation is taking place in a world where there are individuals like Dick Cheney who are trying to justify a policy of rendition, and thus philosophical justifications can can be taken out of context and misconstrued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cenk Ugyur’s response to Harris’ closing statements is certainly true as well. Harris is not in a philosophical seminar, he is in the real world, people take his words seriously, and thus people will use his words with or without context for personal gain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harris’ philosophical approach to these conversations explains his depth, but can also be seen as a weakness. When he goes on interviews like Bill Maher’s, Harris does not have the opportunity to hash out the details of his ideas because the panel interrupts him. On the following day, the media creates sound bites and misrepresents his views. However, the world needs people like Sam Harris to provide a solid definition of good and evil. Harris ventures back and forth between the philosophical world and the real world explaining the nuances of different situations, variables and spectrums. Without a concise understanding of good and evil, people will think with their guts based on thousand year old texts, which ultimately gets gay people killed and witches burned.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/sam-harris-and-ethical-bedrock/&quot;&gt;Sam Harris And Ethical Bedrock&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Raymond Huang at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Raymond Huang&lt;/a&gt; on January 15, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Eric Thomas]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/eric-thomas/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/eric-thomas</id>
  <published>2015-01-07T03:19:25-08:00</published>
  <updated>2015-01-07T03:19:25-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Raymond Huang</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@raymondhuang.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;I listened to an &lt;a href=&quot;http://lewishowes.com/podcast/eric-thomas/&quot; title=&quot;Podcast Episode&quot;&gt;episode&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lewishowes.com/blog/&quot; title=&quot;The School of Greatness&quot;&gt;The School of Greatness&lt;/a&gt; where host Lewis Howes interviews Eric Thomas (ET The Hip Hop Preacher), the voice behind the motivational viral video, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=lsSC2vx7zFQ&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be&quot; title=&quot;How Bad Do You Want It?&quot;&gt;How Bad Do You Want It?&lt;/a&gt;, which is also epically known for the famous quotation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When you want to succeed as bad as you want to breathe, then you will be successful.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the interview, Eric Thomas shares his rags to riches journey, and talks about the importance of determination and hard work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My conclusion from listening to Eric Thomas is that he is a treasure trove of motivational quotations. When discussing work ethos, Eric Thomas, true to his title as The Hip Hop Preacher, preaches:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I got average skill, but I have phenomenal will.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make up for our mediocrity with willpower, he further explains:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I just had to buckle down and really ask myself, what do I really want to do with the rest of my life?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Driving home his point of the potential of hard work, Eric Thomas tells Lewis Howes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I realize that all of us are born with a gift, but you have to hone it… I realize that the gift is not going to create itself, it’s not going to nurture itself, it’s not going to perfect itself. That is something I have to do.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the beginning of the interview, Eric Thomas talks about the videos that went and ultimately propelled him into fame. The video, he says, was “an accident.” The video happened because Eric was “in a room going off on a group of students” because the students “had the opportunity of a lifetime and they weren’t taking advantage of it.” Eric casually puts it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Some guy just happened to have a video camera, just happened to put the mic on me, just happened to use it for his thesis… He never used it for his thesis. Friend of mine put the video up on YouTube, not for the world, but for a place to house content. The video was online for years, and 2 to 3 months after I left my job, the video went viral.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Hip Hop Preacher argues: “that’s greatness”. For him, greatness is being able to “grind for grinding’s sake because you’re passionate about what you do”. He did not sit around for 2 years waiting for the video to go viral. Instead, Eric Thomas buckled down and grinded. Eric Thomas preaches passionately about executing everyday:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“[I’m] waking up every day with this concept [that] I have 24 hours and they are mine. This 24 hours belongs to me. And whatever I do in this 24 hours will determine where I’ll be tomorrow and the next.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“In that 24 hours, I can either break my life, or make my life. What should be on the priority list is going to bed so that [I] can wake up the next day and [I] can grind it out. I’m just a dude that believes that you reap what you sow.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“So if you’re grinding on Monday, grinding on Tuesday, grinding on Wednesday, if you’re grinding 6, 7 days a week for a span of 5 or 6 years, something has got to come out of that.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He concludes, that people should spend more time on figuring out what is needed to be done to “accomplish in this day to live this lifestyle”, and then more people will be successful.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/eric-thomas/&quot;&gt;Eric Thomas&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Raymond Huang at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Raymond Huang&lt;/a&gt; on January 07, 2015.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Want To Be You]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/i-want-to-be-you/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/i-want-to-be-you</id>
  <published>2014-05-11T05:08:50-07:00</published>
  <updated>2014-05-11T05:08:50-07:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Raymond Huang</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@raymondhuang.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bill-clinton-kennedy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bill Clinton&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I came across this image today, it was taken on July 24th 1963, in the White House Rose Garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Clinton had pushed and muscled his way to the front in order to meet the president. Immediately after this famous frame is another scene where Clinton is looking at his hand with this amazed look on his face. It was as if he will never again wash the hand that shook Kennedy’s hand. Following the handshake, Clinton turned around and said to his classmates that someday, he was going to have president Kennedy’s job, that someday, he was going to be the president of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/bill-clinton.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Bill Clinton&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill Clinton has confidence in his gaze. He isn’t intimidated by the position of then president Kennedy, because he sees himself as worthy of that position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Who would have thought that in four months, the man on the right would be dead and in 30 years, the man on the left would be the 42nd president of the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These two images speak volumes about being determined and studious to reach your goals, no matter how high and lofty they are.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/i-want-to-be-you/&quot;&gt;I Want To Be You&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Raymond Huang at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Raymond Huang&lt;/a&gt; on May 11, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pop Artists' Live Performances]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/pop-artists-live-performances/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/pop-artists-live-performances</id>
  <published>2013-12-18T17:05:30-08:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-18T17:05:30-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Raymond Huang</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@raymondhuang.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;p&gt;After going through two Reddit threads about Katy Perry’s singing abilities &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/1t3h1m/katy_perry_gets_caught_lip_syncing_and_is_asked/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reddit.com/r/videos/comments/1t44sj/katy_perry_should_sing_like_this_more_often/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, I have compiled a list of videos that demonstrate various female pop artists’ live singing capabilities, including Katy Perry, Lady Gaga, Miley Cyrus, and P!nk. I feel that Lady Gaga and P!nk are the strongest in terms of their abilitiy to sing and perform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;katy-perry&quot;&gt;Katy Perry&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t be offended that she did a different rendition of the original &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HgzGwKwLmgM&quot; title=&quot;Queen - Don&#39;t Stop me Now&quot;&gt;“Don’t Stop Me Now”&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/GmJHS0dNFD0&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She seems to sing much better when not performing dance moves on stage. Katy Perry’s singing in live performances are not as impressive as studio recordings - she often sounds out of breath and a bit off key. Even though her singing might not be perfect, I like the live performances with the theatrics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/JQU-nS5kP08&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lady-gaga&quot;&gt;Lady Gaga&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are actually many videos on YouTube that show Lady Gaga performing live without any of the theatricals that she is known for. This is just one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/FtOF5wBPDsw&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;miley-cyrus&quot;&gt;Miley Cyrus&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This performance probably has a lot of production and sound engineering incoorporated into it. However, it is nice to see her sing like this sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/wOwblaKmyVw&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;pnk&quot;&gt;P!nk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P!nk and Nate Ruess have an incredible vocal range.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/eSeh009_V1I&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a really good performance. She executes some acrobatics while singing. The acrobatic actions include hanging off the ceiling and spinning around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/embed/3stsDXki__U&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/pop-artists-live-performances/&quot;&gt;Pop Artists&#39; Live Performances&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Raymond Huang at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Raymond Huang&lt;/a&gt; on December 18, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[How To Be Successful]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-be-successful/" />
  <id>http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-be-successful</id>
  <published>2013-12-09T11:39:55-08:00</published>
  <updated>2013-12-09T11:39:55-08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Raymond Huang</name>
    <uri>http://localhost:4000</uri>
    <email>hello@raymondhuang.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">
    &lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&quot;/images/success-kid.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Success Kid&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to be successful, I try to convince myself that working harder than everyone else is much more important than being born talented and smart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2k74r1aoMc0&quot;&gt;Will Smith&lt;/a&gt; believes that he isn’t particularly talented and that his successes are achieved through his “ridiculous [and] sickening work ethic”. Even though “greatness exists in all of us”, not everyone achieves greatness because the “separation of talent and skill is one of the greatest misunderstood concepts”. He explains that everyone can be skilled, and a skill “is only developed by hours and hours and hours of beating on [the] craft” - Malcolm Gladwell anyone? For Will Smith, when others are sleeping, he’s working. When others are eating, he’s working. He “dedicates [himself] to being better every single day”. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=vH0nP4NzS9M&quot;&gt;Arnold Schwarzenegger&lt;/a&gt; also maintains the similar belief that hard work is important to success. He says that “when you’re out there partying, horsing around, someone out there at the same time is working hard, someone is getting smarter and someone is winning”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, the path to success is taken one step at a time. Will Smith argues that the first goal isn’t to “build the biggest, baddest, greatest wall that has ever been built”. Instead, you must first lay a brick, and lay it “as perfectly as a brick can be laid”, and you lay that perfect brick every single day until you have a wall. The underlying advice here is to not set your goals so lofty that it seems daunting and impossible, and that you should not try to take shortcuts. However, each step on the path to success must be taken with hard work and complete dedication - there is no shortcut to working hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does hard work consist of? For &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=GtaxU6DZvLs&quot;&gt;Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt;, it means “work[ing] like hell” and putting in 80 to 100 hours a week. He has done it for years and it certainly “improves the odds of success”. Working at 80 hours a week, you will be able to complete twice as much as the average person and get to your goal twice as fast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course if a person is ambitious enough, by all means, aim for the top, but be wary of the effort that is required. The challenge here, according to Elon Musk, is to identify “the difference between really believing in your ideals and sticking to them as opposed to pursuing some unrealistic dream that doesn’t actually have merit”. Thus, it’s important to be “very rigorous in your self analysis”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, you must also be passionate and really enjoy what you do, no matter the field. If you like what you’re doing, you will “think about it even when you’re not working”, your mind will be drawn to it. If the goal doesn’t hold much meaning, then it’s unlikely you can make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;John Hering, Kevin Mahaffey, and James Burgess, the founders of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.lookout.com/&quot; title=&quot;Lookout&quot;&gt;Lookout&lt;/a&gt;, founded Lookout partly because they are passionate about security. I believe a main reason for Lookout’s success is because they want to solve hard problems and are not afraid to tackle them. I was told that to build a successful business, you cannot be afraid of trying to solve difficult problems. It is unlikely for someone to build the next Candy Crush Saga or Angry Birds with minimal innovations and rake in millions of dollars. King, the company that built Candy Crush Saga, published numerous games before they hit the jackpot. There are no shortcuts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, achieving success involves working hard on something that you are passionate about, dedicating your mind to that goal, and to not be scared away by difficult problems that arise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel that most importantly, I have to be passionate about what I am building and what I want to achieve. Having passion is a great motivator for putting in 80 hours a week into a task. Having passion means that you will want to solve the tough problems that come up, because solving them gets you one step closer to the end result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The caveat of taking advice from these immensely successful individuals is that in addition to their amazing work ethic, all of them are undoubtedly smart and talented. Will Smith was admitted to a pre-engineering program at MIT and his ability to act can be seen throughout all his shows and movies. Arnold Schwarzenegger is a successful business man, bodybuilder, actor, and was also the governor of California. Elon Musk builds electric cars and is going to send mankind to Mars. You have to wonder how much of their successes is due to their talent and innate ability to pursue greatness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless, I believe and I hope that anyone can achieve greatness by emulating these great men.&lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000/blog/how-to-be-successful/&quot;&gt;How To Be Successful&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Raymond Huang at &lt;a href=&quot;http://localhost:4000&quot;&gt;Raymond Huang&lt;/a&gt; on December 09, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;
  </content>
</entry>

</feed>